A Guide to the Executive Mansion and First Lady's Event Records of Virginia Governor George F. Allen, 1994-1997
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Executive Mansion and First Lady's Event Records of Virginia Governor George F. Allen, 1994-1997
The Library of Virginia
35875
2 cu. ft. (2 boxes)
Virginia. Governor (1994-1998: Allen)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred by Georgia Root, Assistant Secretary of the Commonwealth, Richmond, Virginia, 19 June 1998.
Biographical/Historical Information
George Felix Allen was born March 8, 1952 in Whittier, California to famed NFL football coach George H. Allen and his wife Henrietta (Lumbroso) Allen. He graduated from the University of Virginia in 1971 and the University of Virginia School of Law in 1977. Allen served in the Virginia House of Delegates from 1982-1991 and served a short term in the U.S. House of Delegates in the early 1990s. In November 1993, Allen beat Attorney General Mary Sue Terry to become Governor. Governor Allen served until January 1998 and was succeeded by Governor James S. Gilmore. Governor Allen has been married to Susan (Brown) Allen since 1986 and they have three children, Forrest, Tyler, and Brooke. The family resides in Mount Vernon, Virginia.
Scope and Content
Contains records related to functions held at the Executive Mansion as well as events supported and/or attended by First Lady Susan Allen. The first series documents events at the Mansion, while the remaining three series document Mrs. Allen's activities throughout the Commonwealth. Mrs. Allen supported many causes including those related to children, breast cancer awareness, and tourism.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Executive Mansion Events
Series II. Children's Events
Series III. Breast Cancer Awareness and Physical Fitness Events
Series IV. Tourism Events
Contents List
- Series I. Executive Mansion Events, 1994-1997., Extent: 10 folders. (Box 1)
  Includes invitations, menus, guest lists, and seating arrangements for various functions held at the Executive Mansion. Also includes a biographical sketch of Susan Allen and a file devoted to the Citizens' Advisory Council on Furnishing and Interpreting the Executive Mansion.
  Function files are arranged chronologically.
  - First Lady Susan Allen's Biography. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Functions, 1994 January-February. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Functions, 1994 March-October. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Functions, 1994 March-October. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Functions, 1994 November-1995 March. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Functions, 1995 April-September. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Functions, 1995 October-1996 November. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Functions, 1996 December-1997 April. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Functions, 1997 April-November. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Citizens' Advisory Council on Furnishing and Interpreting the Executive Mansion. (Box 1, Folder 9A)
- Series II. Children's Events, 1994-1997., Extent: 43 folders. (Box 1)
  Includes programs, speeches, and organizational literature that documents numerous children's events held throughout the Commonwealth and attended by First Lady Susan Allen. The First Lady was often invited to be the featured speaker and to serve as an honoray chairperson for the event.
  Arrangement is loosely chronological.
  - Children's Issues (News Clips and Press Releases), 1994-1997. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Rural Point Elementary School, 1995 January. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Club RAPP, 1994 December. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Toy and Food Drive, 1994 December. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Red Ribbon Week, 1994 October. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Girl Scouts Investiture Ceremony, 1994 October. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ABC College Awards, 1994 October. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - St. Mary's Infant Home, 1994 October. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Arts Council Children's Festival, 1994 October. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University Mentoring Event, 1994 October. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Crimestoppers, 1994 September. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Discovery Works (Radford), 1994 September. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Greenville "CARES" Luncheon, 1994 September. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Week of the Child Activities, 1994 April. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Children's Hospital 75th Anniversary Celebration, 1995 April. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Sesame Street 25th Birthday, 1994 April. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Big Brothers/Big Sisters Ribbon-Cutting, 1994 June. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Rainbow Gala (Association for the Study of Childhood Cancer), 1994 September. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Prevent Child Abuse Fashion Show, 1995 February. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Maybeury Elementary Visit, 1995 April. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Moonlight Walk (King's Daughters), 1995 May. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Make-A-Wish Foundation, 1995 September. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Battlefield Park Elementary School, 1995 November. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Child Abuse Prevention Month Kick-off, 1996 April. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Robious Elementary Visit, 1996 March. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Girl Scout Public Service Announcement, 1996 February. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Rural Point Elementary School, 1996 January. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Martinsville DARE Rally, 1996 April. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Youth Service Week Event, 1996 April. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Henrico Schools Event, 1996 September. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - First Lady's Trail Ride (4-H Foundation), 1996 October. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - First Lady's Trail Ride (4-H Foundation), 1996 October. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Big Help Day, 1996 November. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - D.M.V. Contest Awards, 1996 December. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - 4-H Ambassadors Visit, 1997 February. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Circus School Event, 1997 February. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Substance Abuse Prevention Awards, 1997 March. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Richmond Library Reading Time, 1997 March. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Youth Service Event, 1997 April. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Virginia Home for Boys Luncheon, 1997 June. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Carver Elementary School Visit, 1997 September. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Japan-Virginia Society (Japan Girl Scout Event), 1997. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - First Lady's Trail Ride (4-H Foundation), 1997 November. (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Series II. Breast Cancer Awareness and Physical Fitness Events, 1994-1997., Extent: 53 folders. (Box 1-2)
  Includes programs, speeches, and organizational literature that document Susan Allen's involvement in promoting breast cancer awareness and education throughout the Commonwealth. Also included at the end of this series are files that document Mrs. Allen's involvement with physical fitness-related events.
  - Breast Cancer Awareness (News Clips and Press Releases), 1994-1997. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Cancer Society Fundraiser (Margaret Phillips), 1994 September. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - University of Virginia Breast Cancer Forum, 1994 October. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Galax Radio Phone-in (Breast Cancer), 1994 October. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Breast Cancer Awareness Leadership Forum, 1995 April. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Wytheville Mammography Unit, 1995 April. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Tell a Friend Public Service Announcement, 1995 September. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Charlottesville-Albemarle Breast Cancer Relay for Life, 1995 September. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Breast Cancer Awareness Month Kick-off, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Breast Cancer Awareness Press Conference, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Golf Tournament for Breast Cancer, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Fairfax Breast Cancer Events, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Breast Cancer Awards, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Galax Breast Cancer Event, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Riverside Diagnostic Center, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Hampton Breast Cancer Event, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Sweet Briar College Breast Cancer Forum, 1995 October. (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Virginia Breast and Cervical Cancer Coalition, 1995 November. (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Virginia Breast Cancer Foundation Symposium, 1995 November. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University/University of Richmond Brain Tumor Research Classic, 1996 January. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Women's Health Passport Press Event, 1996 January. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Face of Breast Cancer Exhibit Tea and Press Conference, 1996 September. (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Coalition for Every Woman's Life (Breast Cancer Awareness), 1996 October. (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Richmond American Cancer Society Women's Golf Championship, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Fluvanna County Breast Cancer Awareness Forum, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Tappahannock Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - WLEE Breast Cancer Awareness Announcement, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Waynesboro Breast Health Coalition Reception, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Danville Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Blackstone Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Norton Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Farmville Breast Cancer Awareness Reception, D1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Catholic Women's Club, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Breast Cancer Awareness Mansion Reception, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Roanoke Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Franklin Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Massey Cancer Center Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Breast Cancer Foundation Volunteer Reception, 1997 January. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Evelyn Lauder Lunch (Massey Cancer Center), 1997 February. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Massey Cancer Center, 1997 February. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Race for the Cure, 1997 February. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Board of Women's Health Gala, 1997 April. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Relay for Life (University of Richmond), 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ukrop's Breast Cancer Awareness Public Service Announcement, 1997 September. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Ladykiller Tour Event, 1997 September. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Front Royal and Winchester Breast Cancer Awareness Events, 1997 October. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Tidewater Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1997 October. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Spotsylvania Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1997 October. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - University of Virginia Every Woman's Life Event, 1997 October. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Southwest Breast Cancer Awareness Event, 1997 October. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - National Girls and Women in Sports Day Celebration, 1996 February. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Governor's Commission on Physical Fitness and Sports, 1997 September. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Women in Sports Day Walk, 1996 February. (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Series IV. Tourism Events, 1994-1997., Extent: 61 folders. (Box 2)
  Includes programs, speeches, organizational literature, invitations to conferences, and conference literature that documents Susan Allen's involvement in promoting Virginia tourism and industry, both domestically and abroad.
  - Tourism Press Clips and Press Releases, 1994. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Heritage Tourism Week, 1994. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Forbes Reception (Civil War Love Letters), 1994 November. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Southwest Virginia Annual Tourism Conference, 1994 November. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Cape Town Mayoral Visit (Mt. Vernon), 1994 September. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Alexandria Hotel Association, 1994 September. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Virginia Recreation and Park Society, 1994 September. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Familiarization Tour Event, 1994 September. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Scotchtown, 1994 May. (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - New Kent Groundbreaking, 1994 September. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Richmond International Raceway, 1994 September. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Tourism Press Clips and Press Releases, 1995. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Kings Dominion Event, 1995 April. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Tour DuPont, 1995 April. (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Heritage Tourism Week, 1995. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Francis Land House, 1995 May. (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Virginia Tech Tourism Interview, 1995 May. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - South African Tourism Meeting, 1995 May. (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Explore Park, 1995 June. (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Travelhost National Awards Ceremony, 1995 September. (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Southeast Tourism Award Ceremony, 1995 September. (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Virginia Thanksgiving Festival, 1995 November. (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - State Parks Public Service Announcement, 1995 January. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Tourism Press Clips and Press Releases, 1996. (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Heritage Tourism Week Public Service Announcement, 1996 February. (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Virginia Hospitality and Travel Association's Government Action Day, 1996 January. (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Hampton Roads Festival and Event Association Meeting, 1996 April. (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Virginia Museum of Natural History, 1996 April. (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Abingdon Visit, 1996 April. (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Los Angeles Events (Virginia Film Office), 1996 May. (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Virginia Tourism Appreciation Day, 1996 May. (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Virginia Hospitality and Travel Association Award Luncheon, 1996 September. (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Today Show, 1996 June. (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Faberge Ball, 1996 September. (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Virginia is for Lovers Symposium, 1996 September. (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - New Millennium Studio (First Lady's Announcement), 1996 October. (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Travel and Tourism Class Visit (Virginia Randolph Community High), 1996 December. (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Tourism News Clips and Press Releases, 1997. (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Japanese Journal Interview, 1997 January. (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - State Parks Public Service Announcement, 1997 January. (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Lewis Ginter Botanical Garden Groundbreaking, 1997 March. (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Operation Spruce Up, 1997 April. (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Homestead Wine Event, 1997 April. (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Waterfront Festival Luncheon, 1997 April. (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Virginia Sports Hall of Fame, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Southeastern Virginia Tourism Summit, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Natural Bridge Events, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Bonnie Blue Horse Show, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Frontier Museum, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Historic Downtown Richmond (Valentine), 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Montross Heritagefest, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Virginia Creeper Trail Bike Ride, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Tour de Chesapeake Photographs (copies), 1997. (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Time Travelers Event (Virginia Historical Society), 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Chateau Morrisette, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Marion, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Race for the Cure, 1997 June. (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Keep Virginia Beautiful Awards, 1997 October. (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Virginia Living Museum Interview, 1997 November. (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Celebrate Virginia, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Celebrate Virginia, 1997 May. (Box 2, Folder 91)